[♪ mysterious music playing]
[CAPTAIN]
Checking the landing area.
[BALCUS] I want us ready
to disembark. Hurry!
[indistinct chatter]
Everyone's off the ship.
We are heading back into battle.
Excuse me, sir.
We're going with you.
[BALCUS] You boys
are in no shape to fight.
It's best you remain here
with the other evacuees.
But we can--
[CLARICE] Don't be so stubborn,
you two.
You've both already proven
your courage 10 times over.
[RAYMOND] Really? You think so?
Absolutely.
And Leon will be fine.
I mean, you trust him, right?
Yeah, of course.
I mean, why wouldn't we?
Wait, what am I saying?
What a crock!
[groans]
[Leon, Vandel grunting]
♪
[COMMANDER] At this rate,
we'll be wiped out!
[Leon, Vandel grunting]
[grunts]
What were you expecting,
you amateur?
Merging with that odd vehicle
didn't do much to help you,
did it? [coughs]
[gasps]
[clears throat]
Villains of the kingdom
have earned no mercy.
The same kindness
you extended to us!
[LUXION] My assessment is that
he has lost his mind.
The magical item
has completely taken over.
[LEON] Damn it.
Are you that desperate
to keep fighting?
Surrender!
[yells]
[♪ opening theme song playing]
Wait a sec.
I know a way
to stop that monster.
[Julius gasps]
Are you sure, Marie?
-I mean, Lady Marie?
-Yeah.
I only took a quick look
at the cutscene
when I opened
my brother's save file, but...
[CLEARE] The monster
is being controlled
by some item
called the magic flute.
She's right. It happened
back during our school trip.
I saw monsters
being summoned firsthand.
[JILK] But where is it?
[CLEARE] I am detecting
the source
of the instrument's sound
on that ship.
We have no choice.
This suffering cannot continue.
Roger.
Head over
and stop whoever's playing it!
Please.
Who do you think you are?
You can't order us around.
[MARIE] How are you all
so freaking clueless?!
Whatever. Just do it!
[KYLE] Honestly, mistress,
you're as impetuous as ever.
[Leon grunting]
Something wrong?
Is that all you got?!
Give it up already, gramps!
[growls]
[MARIE] Watch out!
Damn it!
♪
[all screaming]
[MARIE] I can't
take this anymore!
[CLEARE] How very
unsaintly of her.
And really,
she need not be so concerned.
Why, Clearey?
[CLEARE] Did you
give me a nickname
to indicate familiarity?
That is most congenial of you.
As for why I am confident
of our success,
that is because we have
a certain sourpuss escorting us.
[LUXION] Energy fully charged.
Firing boson particle cannon.
[JULIUS] Whoa!
What was that beam?
I've never seen magic
like that before!
[Cleare laughs]
Yes, that is right.
It is magic.
Incredibly powerful magic.
No. It's something else.
[BOTH] Surely
the demon lord's wrath!
[The Final Boss growling]
Hurry up, Kyle!
Before that monster
has time to regenerate!
Yes, I'm working on it.
[JULIUS] Follow my lead!
We'll provide backup!
[ALL] Don't tell us what to do!
[all panting]
[MARIE] There's the magic flute!
Told ya!
That girl.
Hertrude!
How did you get here?
Wait, were you playing it?
[♪ somber music playing]
I'll destroy every
last one of them.
Please, you have to stop this.
At this rate,
there won't be anyone left!
So what?
What are you saying?
Your own people will be killed
because of you!
We can end this right now!
-No.
-[gasps]
-I must see it through.
-You mustn't.
If you wanna kill me,
then go ahead and do it!
Even if I die, it won't halt
the guardian of the land!
-It'll just keep reviving!
-[gasps]
[ANGELICA] I understand
you hate us,
and you have every right,
but what's the point
of continuing this?
All you'll do is cause
more needless deaths!
Oh, shut up.
[ANGELICA] Don't forget
the principality can trace
its roots back
to the Holfort royals.
[scoffs]
Believe me, I know.
But the simple fact is
I don't care
what happens anymore.
[both gasp]
Excuse me?
That's right.
I don't care what happens
to the principality
after the way they exploited us,
me and my sister.
Turns out they were the ones
who killed our parents.
We never realized
we were being manipulated.
[gasps softly]
[HERTRUDE] Everything I loved
has been stolen from me.
Even my sister, Rauda!
I don't trust anyone!
As far as I'm concerned,
they should be erased!
I want nothing
from this hopeless world
except its total destruction!
My family was ripped away!
I've earned the right
to avenge them! Haven't I?
We were innocent kids.
-Didn't we deserve to be happy?
-[gasps]
[HERTRUDE] Well?!
Still, it's wrong!
Taking your rage
out on the world!
What's revenge going to achieve?
Besides, this isn't what
your sister would've wanted.
[MARIE] You moron!
Stop dreaming!
I swear, you're living
in a fantasy world!
-[gasps]
-[gasps] Miss Marie?
Hey, wait. What are you saying?
Whose side are you on?
Sorry, which side?
I'm with team reality!
Stop spouting
idealistic nonsense!
You think revenge
is so terrible?
You know her life?
What she's been through?
Suddenly you're an expert on
what her sister wouldn't want?
And who even told you
you had the right
to speak on her behalf anyway?
-Pipe down!
-You're right, but--
All the misery
she's been through,
and you expected her
to lie down and take it?!
She deserves happiness
like anyone else!
Did you ever
once think about her feelings?
You don't have
any problem lecturing her,
but if you lost your loved ones,
would you just
throw your arms in the air?
You're telling me
you wouldn't fight,
even if it was wrong?
I'm... I'm not sure what--
I bet you've never felt
soul-crushing regret!
Have you ever lost
anyone close to you?
Realized you'd never
see them again?!
Take it from me!
There's no worse feeling
in the world,
and it never
completely goes away!
Fine! We get it!
But finding a way
to stop that monster
should be our priority!
You don't get it!
If this is all it takes
to destroy this stupid world,
I say let it crumble!
And yeah,
of course I know it's wrong
and that we shouldn't
let it happen, but...
it's also wrong
to let people go unpunished!
[inhales]
[♪ playing melody]
[all gasp]
[growling]
[exhales]
-Who would've thought?
-[gasps]
Of all the people
who would come to my defense,
the Saint who only cares
about money was willing
to stand up for me.
[scoffs]
Is that what you think?
Because I wasn't.
I just couldn't stand these two
and their
"main character" syndrome.
I'm still glad you spoke up,
or I never would've
felt this way.
Yeah, whatever.
So, are you really okay
with this?
Of course not.
[sighs] I didn't want it
to go this far.
I'm through.
[growling]
[gasps]
Hurry. You have to leave.
Get as far away
from me as possible.
[ALL] Huh?
[ANGELICA] What's wrong?
[HERTRUDE] The cost
of summoning guardians
with the instrument
is the user's life.
I've broken the contract,
and the consequences
will be severe.
I will never be able
to play this flute again.
The guardian will kill me
for breaking our agreement.
Stop this!
No, but...
The principality surrenders.
We're defeated.
[growling]
[Vandel grunts, coughs]
[both grunting]
[CLEARE] Everyone, stand clear!
-[slams]
-[all gasp]
[ANGELICA] Livia!
Are you all right?
[HERTRUDE] Vandel!
[LEON] Is that...
It is. Why are they down there?
[gasps]
And Princess Hertrude's
with them?!
[Vandel straining]
[Purple Goo monster growling]
[gasps]
Vandel,
there's no need to fight!
As Princess of Fanoss,
I've declared our defeat!
[Purple Goo monster growling]
[VANDEL] Princess, do not worry.
I'll kill
that villain momentarily.
[vomits, coughs]
I'll crush the kingdom's forces
and wipe them from existence.
[HERTRUDE] Didn't you hear me?
We lost, Vandel! It's over!
[groans] Not for me, Princess.
[♪ somber music playing]
[young Hertrauda sobbing]
Are you sure?
There was no other choice
available to us?
The nobility
and common people agree
war with the kingdom
is in our interest.
So, yes,
the only option we had
was to do away
with the king and queen.
But there's no point
crying over it now.
Buck up, you'll get revenge
for your family soon enough.
If you're truly a knight
of the principality,
put aside your useless regrets.
[gasps]
[young Hertrauda sobbing]
-[VANDEL] Princesses.
-[gasps]
Vandel.
I will protect you.
Both of you girls.
And while I know I can
never replace your parents,
I will fight for you
and your sister in their stead.
Really? Will you?
♪
I swear to you upon this sword!
This cannot end.
This cannot be the end!
Vandel.
[VANDEL] I shall fight
until I'm killed
and continue even afterwards.
That's the only way I can find
any sort of redemption.
I both live and die.
By the code of chivalry!
-[yells]
-[both grunt]
[groans]
[LEON] Die!
Bastard!
[gasps]
[both grunt]
[grunts]
[laughs]
[gasps]
[gasping]
Damn it!
[groans]
Luxion!
[VANDEL] I'm taking you
with me! [gasps]
[LEON] Sorry, old-timer.
You're on your own.
[LUXION] Impact.
[screaming]
[HERTRUDE] Vandel!
[growling]
[Purple Goo monster squealing]
[grunts]
[HERTRUDE] Vandel!
You can't die! Stay with me!
Say something!
My dear princess, I...
This is goodbye.
My final battle has been fought.
Don't say that!
You're the only family
I've got left!
I know. I'm sorry.
[MARIE] You heard her!
You don't have permission
to croak!
What? Have you lost it?
You know he's the Black Knight?
Duh, of course.
After all the problems
he's caused us, how could I not?
But that doesn't matter.
[gasps]
[♪ somber music playing]
Well, jerk? You gonna be selfish
and leave her all alone?
[gasps]
[grumbles]
[VANDEL] Good.
There are others like me.
People who care
about the princess.
I can finally rest.
You've won, boy.
Promise me one thing.
Anything.
Find happiness in this life.
Vandel!
[sobbing]
-[rumbling]
-[all gasp]
[growls]
[growling]
Hey. What did I just tell you?
You can't stay here.
Unless you wanna die with me.
-B-But...
-[gasps]
[CLEARE] Come along,
both of you.
And please hurry.
[growling]
[HERTRUDE] Let's end this.
[whooshing]
[gasps]
[♪ gentle music playing]
Leon, you're staying?
I should have known.
I'm in position.
So now what, bud?
[LUXION] Against an endlessly
regenerating enemy,
I fear your options are limited.
Additionally, Olivia has been
-severely weakened.
-[CLEARE] Luxion.
What's up?
[LUXION] Understood, Cleare.
The main ship is out of range,
so I shall gather energy
in the Arroganz.
[LEON] What do you mean
out of range?
Like, for what?
[LUXION] Olivia's power.
Mr. Leon.
[LEON] Livia. Angie.
[LUXION] I will add
her wavelength to your attack.
[LEON] It's time to go big
or go home.
[growls]
[monsters growling]
[JULIUS] Don't let them
get close!
[ALL] Don't tell us what to do!
♪
[LUXION] Fabulous.
[growling]
[cracking]
-[shatters]
-[gasps]
[HERTRUDE] He didn't have to,
but he saved me.
[SOLDIER 1]
The monster's been killed!
-[SOLDIER 2] We did it!
-[all soldiers cheering]
[LEON] All in a day's work.
So much for the final boss.
[LUXION] So much for Arroganz.
-It has reached its limit.
-[Leon gasps, screams]
[screaming]
-[Olivia gasps]
-[ANGELICA] Leon!
[CLEARE] Oh, you boys. [giggles]
[waves lapping]
[LEON] Look.
Be brutally honest,
did I do the right thing?
I'm supposed to be
an unimportant mob,
living an unimportant life
and minding my own business.
But tons of people
ended up dying,
and I was responsible
for a lot of those deaths.
If a protagonist type
had been calling the shots,
would things
have turned out differently?
[LUXION] You overestimate
your importance.
The war would've happened
either way.
And it is not like
anybody expected much from you.
[scoffs] Know what?
You can be a real dick.
[sighs]
That's me. Just an NPC
with no bearing on this world.
Regardless,
I'm surprised we won.
[♪ gentle music playing]
[LUXION] Why is that?
Because this world subscribed
to the rules of your
so-called "otome game"?
Huh? I'm not following.
[LUXION] You are
always complaining
about how trite
and contrived everything is.
In the end, are you surprised?
-Love was the answer.
-[gasps]
[Leon laughing]
[water splashes]
Leon!
Mr. Leon!
They're safe. Good.
[LUXION] You may be
just a non-player character,
but their feelings for you
are real.
The truth is, that is
what ended the fighting.
Is it not about time
you made your decision
for their sake?
You do love them, correct?
[LEON] I don't think you get it.
I want to take care of them both
because I love them.
I haven't given much thought
to what I'm gonna say,
but for now,
I think this will do.
We made it.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[LEON] The fighting's over!
Peace has been restored,
- and my brother's engaged?!
-[LUXION] Master.
[LEON] Ya boi's screams echo
across an inescapable future!
-[LUXION] Master?
-[LEON] The final episode,
"This World Is Tough for Mobs."
Turns out the final boss
of life is freakin' romance!